

+65 9776 9779



93edwinotw@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/edwinotw/



github.com/EdwinOTW



edwinotw.github.io



Skills

Python Machine Learning SQL Html / CSS Keras / Tensorflow

Microsoft Office Financial Analysis Data Visualization Tableau

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Lightroom Final Cut Pro

Certificates / Awards

CFA Level I Candidate

Certificate in Math for Engineering Aircraft Basic Maintanence **Training**

CMFAS (M5, M9, M9a, HI, GI)

Hobbies

Video Production Gym, Hiking Poker, ESports

Edwin Ong Tze Wei

Data Analyst

Personal Statement

Business-minded Data Analyst with strong analytical skills from my Investment and Financial background achieved through 1 year of work in Temasek Holdings and my Banking and Finance Degree. I believe in maximizing your organization's business potential and profits by using data-driven solutions and machine learning to solve any challenging business problems your organization faces.

Education

Data Science Immersive

General Assembly 2019 - 2019

- (Project) Machine Learning / Data Visualization to predict West NIIe Virus (Unbalanced Dataset)
- (Project) Machine Learning to predict Stock Market Reversal points (Time Series, Unbalanced Dataset)
- (Project) Machine Learning Classification Models for subreddit (NLP)

BSc Banking and Finance (1st Class Honors)

Singapore Institute of Management (University of London) 2015 - 2018

Experience

Private Equity Funds Investment - Officer

Temasek Holdings | Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

Analyzed Financial and Quarterly Reports received from funds, identified and captured all the important fundamental performance metrics from respective underlying portfolio companies

- Meticulous Compilation of data for over 300 different funds managed by Temasek and over 1000 underlying portfolio companies into usable format for further analysis
- Assisted with AdHoc projects and delivered within deadline

Operations and Finance Intern

Airfrov | June 2017 - Sep 2017

Served as a point of contact for all customer's enquiries through excellent customer service skills and took the role of CEO's Personal Assistant

- Reduced customer enquiry response time from 5 to 1 working day
- Product Quality Assurance
- Managed up to 100 customers credit transactions daily with 100% accuracy
- Liaised with logistic companies to send out products
- Quality check and conduct interviews with potential job applicants